"The 100" 지난 이야기...
Previously on "The 100"...
너흰 지상으로 가게 될꺼야.
You're being sent to the ground.
마지막 전투가 벌어지기 전,
Before the last war, Mount Weather was
웨더산 내부에 군기지를 만들었었다.
a military base built within a mountain.
써먹진 못했었지만 말이네.
No one ever made it there.
웨더산에 올 걸 환영한다.
Welcome to Mount Weather.
넌 죄수가 아니란다.
You're not prisoners.
우린 널 구출한거야.
We saved you.
여길 왜 떠나고 싶어하겠어?
Why would we want to leave?
저 밖에 우리 도움을
기다리는 친구들이 있으니까.
We have friends out
there who need our help.
클라크, 안돼!
Clarke, no!
네가 손잡이를 당겨버린다면,
이 분들은 다 죽게될까라고.
If you pull that lever,
these people will die.
아주 적은 방사선도
이 분들에겐 치명적이야.
Even a little radiation could kill them.
진심으로 "Ark"를...
Are we really gonna do this,
착륙시키겠단 겁니까?
bring the Ark to the ground?
좀 어떤가? 말해보게
Tell me what it's like.
꿈만 같아요.
Everything I dreamed.
셀로니어스, 당신께서도 여기 계셨어야했는데...
Thelonious, you should be here.
내 소임은 다 한거 같군, 그럼 이만.
My job is done. Jaha out.
네가 죽는 줄 알았어.
I thought you died.
날 네 마을로 데려온거야?
You brought me to your village?
놈들이 널 죽일꺼라고..
They'll kill you.
개새끼야!
You son of a bitch!
억!
Unh!
이젠 네가 맘대로 설치게 놔둘순 없다.
You are not in control here anymore.
열게.
Open it up.
예
Yes, sir.
언제까지 절
How long are you gonna keep me
여기 가둬놓을 셈입니까?
locked up in here?
자네가 다른 사람에게 해를 끼치지 않을 것이라고
Until I'm confident you're no longer
내가 확신할 수 있을 때까지.
a threat to others.
그럼 계속 해볼까.
Let's continue.
자넨 수백명의 지상인들이 공격해왔다고 했지
Now you said there were
hundreds of Grounders attacking.
200, 300?
세보진 않았습니다.
I didn't count.
놈들이 왜 공격해온 것 같나?
Why do you think they attacked?
놈들을 자극했나?
What provoked them?
우리의 존재 자체, 그게 전부였습니다.
We were here. That was enough.
이건 시간 낭비입니다.
We're wasting time.
다른 얘들은 그냥 땅으로 꺼진게 아닙니다.
The others didn't just
vanish into thin air.
잡혀간거죠, 쫓아가서 구해야 합니다.
They were taken, and we
need to go after them.
수색팀이 준비중이네,
Search team is prepping to leave
허나 먼저 자네에게
그에 관한 정보부터 얻어야겠지.
but not before we've gotten
the intel we need from you.
저도 수색팀에 포함시켜 주십쇼, 부탁드립니다.
I need to be on that team, please.
말도 안되는 소리네.
That's out of the question.
자넨 적합한 훈련을 받은 적도 없네.
You're not trained.
너무 위험하지.
It's too dangerous.
그 녀석들은 제 사람들 입니다.
Those are my people out there.
내 사람들이기도 하지.
They're my people, too.
그들을 돕고 싶나?
You want to help them?
말해주게.. 어떤 놈들과 맞서야하는 것인지..
Tell me what we're up against...
지상인들의 전략, 규모
Grounder tactics, their numbers,
어떤 병기를 사용하는지...
what kind of weapons they used.
활과 창, 도끼, 칼,
Arrows and spears, axes, swords,
이빨.
their teeth.
총은?
No guns?
자네들은 총이 있었어.
You had guns.
보급창에서 발견한 총기들을 말씀하시는 거군요..
The guns we found at the aid depot
전력차를 좁혀줬었죠.
leveled the playing field,
총알이.. 조금만.. 조금만 더 있었더라면..
and maybe, maybe if we'd had
more bullets, we could have...
총알은 더 있었네.
There were more bullets.
수색팀들이 다녀왔네.
Search team just returned from the bunker.
라이플 2상자와
They found two more barrels full of rifles
탄약 3상자를 발견했지.
and a third filled with bullets.
좀더 샅샅히 뒤져봤어야 했는데..
We should have looked harder.
계속 걸어.
Keep walking.
뭡니까?
What's he doing here?
방해해서 죄송합니다. 그리핀 선생님이
머피씨가 퇴원해도 좋다고 하더군요.
Excuse me, sir. Dr. Griffin
cleared Mr. Murphy out of medical.
저기 데려다 놓게, 브랫 소령.
Put him over there, Major Byrne.
무릎꿇어
On your knees.
어서
Come on.
참 신나기도 하겠군..
Well, this should be fun.
가자!
Let's go!
얼른, 얼른!
Move, move, move!
뛰어 뛰어!
Go, go, go!
저기! 놈들이 저기 있었습니다!
There! They were right there!
뭐라도 본사람 있나?
Did anyone see anything?
어떤 놈들 이었나? 몇명이나 있었지?
Who was there? How many?
어떻게 생긴 놈들 이었지?
What did they look like?
잘 모르겠습니다, 하지만 분명
I don't know, but I'm sure I saw
누군가 움직였던건 확실합니다.
someone move.
근데 총을 쐈다고?
You opened fire?
- 그 얘들일수도 있다고.
- 에비!
- That could have been the kids.
- Abby!
안돼.
No.
숲속을 수색시키겠소.
We'll sweep the woods.
그전에, 누가 자네에게 무기를 지급했지?
In the meantime, who
issued you that weapon?
접니다.
I did, sir.
지금부턴,
From now on,
군인에게만 총을 지급하도록.
only members of the guard get guns.
총기 무단 사용은
Unauthorized use of firearms
중범죄로
will be punishable as a felony
엄중히 처벌할 것이다,
under the Exodus Charter.
알아들었나?
Is that clear?
예
Yes, sir.
마르커스, 망할 숲부터 좀 찾아봐주시죠.
Marcus, search the damn woods.
3번 분대! 출동한다!
Move out! Teams of 3!
예
Yes, ma'am!
5분마다 무전으로 보고해라,
Radio checks at 5-minute intervals.
가자!
Let's go!
괜찮네.
It's not bad.
어쩌면 언젠가 여기 벽에
걸어줄지도 모르겠는걸?
Maybe they'll hang it on
the walls here one day.
밀러!
Miller!
봐, 결국 퇴원했네.
Look who finally got released.
헤이!
Hey.
밀러.
Miller.
좋아보여 다행이야.
I'm glad you're ok.
그랴, 뭐 3번쯤 수술했나?
Yeah. Only took, what, 3 surgeries?
잘지내고 있다고 들었는데.
I hear you're fitting right in.
하루에 2번, 잊지말고 먹어요.
Twice a day. Don't forget.
며칠만 지나면 다 나을꺼에요.
You'll be ok in a few days.
- 여기.
- 감사합니다.
- Here.
- Thanks.
마야 씨, 아침에 그 난리통을
Maya, top of the morning...
겪고난 다음에 하기엔
is a very dumb thing to say that I saw
좀 바보같은 질문이지만..
in an old move once.
그니까, 아침 먹으러 갈까요?
Hey. You going to breakfast?
그래. 같이 갈까?
Yeah. You want to go together?
물론, 좋죠. 그러니까 설라무네 완전 좋죠.
Sure, yeah. I... I'd love t...
음, 다음에 같이 먹자, 응?
Um, save me a seat, ok?
미안.
Sorry.
저기, 무슨 일이지?
Hey. What's going on?
지상 순찰팀이 돌아왔는데,
That signal means the
surface patrol is back
의료지원을 요하는 인원이 있다는 신호에요.
and someone needs medical attention.
격리구역으로 가봐야해요.
I have to go to quarantine.
야, 클라크. 뭐하는거야?
Hey, Clarke. What are you doing?
생존자들을 발견할걸지도 몰라,
Maybe they found survivors.
만약 우리 사람들이 다친거라면,
바로 알아야겠어.
If our people are hurt,
we have a right to know.
내 생각엔 우리가 함부로
I'm pretty sure we shouldn't just go
돌아다니지 않는게 나을거 같은데..
w... wandering around.
어떤 상황이죠?
What are we dealing with?
공격받았대, 한 명은 사망했고. 시신은 2번방에 안치했다는군.
They were attacked. One
dead. He's in room two.
다른 한 명은 그를 치료해보려고
장갑과 방독면을 벗었었대,
The other took off his
gloves and mask to treat him.
아직 검역중이긴 한데 끝나는대로
He's still in decon,
but he'll need treatment
치료가 필요하다더군.
as soon as he's processed through.
누가 그들을 공격한거죠?
Who attacked them?
저 사람들 여기서 뭐하는 건가?
What are they doing here?
이봐, 멈춰! 위험하다고!
Hey, stop! It's not safe!
우릴 위한거라고.
It is for us.
제스퍼 가자.
Let's go, Jasper.
하여간 골칫덩이라니까..
Someone's got to keep her out of trouble.
클라크, 천천히 좀 가!
Clarke, slow down!
막무가내로 행동하지 좀 마. 이 사람들은...
Stop pushing so hard. These people are...
우리에게 구라쳤지.
Are lying to us.
이건 총상이야.
That's a bullet wound.
지상인들은 총을 쓰지 않지.
Grounders don't use guns.
우리 총 뺏어가기 전 얘기지.
Unless the Grounders got the guns from us.
내 생각은 달라.
I don't think so.
걔들은 살아있어.
I think our people are alive out there.
이 놈들 끌어내!
Get them out of here.
좀 어떠니?
How are you feeling?
죽여주네요.
Awesome.
뻥치는거에요.
She's lying.
내가 저 표정 뭔지 잘 알지.
걍 말해줘요, 에비.
I know that face. Just spit it out, Abby.
총알이 아직도 유동하고 있어.
The bullet is still shifting.
그래서 고통이 가시질 않는거야.
That's why you're in pain.
지금쯤이면 안정될 거라 기대했는데..
I was hoping that it
would stabilize by now.
그래서 어떻게 빼내시려구요?
So how about you take it out?
레이븐, 말해둘께 있는데...
Raven, we need to talk about that.
총알이 척추를 압박하고 있어.
The bullet is pressing on your spine.
그냥 냅두면, 살긴 하겠지만...
If we leave it in, you'll live,
걸을 수 없게 될꺼야.
but you'll never walk again.
제거하면요?
And take it out?
수술 중에 죽을 수도 있어.
The surgery could kill you.
수술장비도, 마취제도 없어.
We have no equipment,
we have no anesthesia.
걸을 순 있을까요?
Will I walk again?
어쩌면, 하지만 수술하는 동안 깨어있어야 해.
Maybe, but you'd be awake the whole time.
모든 고통을 견뎌내면서 말야.
You'd feel everything.
그렇게 해주세요.
Sign me up.
기려다봐 레이븐, 너 죽을지도 모른다고..
Wait. Raven, you could die.
무중력 상태에서야 다리따윈 필요없었지만,
In Zero G I didn't need my legs.
이 아래에선, 필요해.
Down here, I do.
제거해주세요.
Take it out.
링컨은 어딨어?
Where's Lincoln?
마셔라.
Drink.
마시든지 죽든지, 니 맘대로해라.
Drink or die. Your choice.
전부다.
All of it.
얘기좀 하시죠.
We need to talk.
얼마든지. 아침이나 들면서 얘기하도록 하세.
Sure. Let's talk over breakfast.
누가 그 병사를 쏜거죠?
Who shot that solider?
순찰대는 자네 사람들을 찾다가
The patrol that was looking for your people
자네들이 지상인이라 부르는 사람들에게 공격당했다네.
was attacked by what you call Grounders.
지상인들과 이미 싸워본 적 있어요.
I fought Grounders.
놈들은 총을 쓰지 않죠.
They don't use guns.
난 총이라고 한 적 없네만..
I never mentioned guns.
쇼우 상사는 화살에 맞았다네.
Sergeant Shaw was shot by an arrow.
아니거든요, 제가.. 제가 상처를 봤다구요.
That's not true. I... I saw the wound.
가끔, 자기 사람들을 너무 걱정한 나머지
Sometimes, we feel so
strongly about our people
잘못 볼 수도 있지.
we see things that aren't there.
시신을 보고 싶은데요.
I'd like to see the body.
그러렴.
Of course.
같이 가자꾸나.
Come with me.
나도 "공기"가 별로 대단찮은 건 알고 있다만,
I know the air's not that great,
그게 우리가 가진 전부로구나.
but that's all we got left.
참 엉망진창이야, 그렇잖니?
We're in a fine mess now, aren't we?
그치만 널 여기서 죽게 내버려둘 순 없지.
But I can't let you die up here with me.
그래.
Yes.
아무래도 (가만히 있기보단) 널 지상으로
데려갈 방법을 찾는게 낫겠어, 응?
I guess we better find a way
to get you to the ground, huh?
어때. 맘에 드니?
Yeah. You like that idea?
오. 그래그래.
Ooh. Ok. Ok.
자 그럼 이제, 그래.
Come on. Ok now, ok.
이 위에 우릴 살려줄만한게
남아있나 한번 볼까?
Let's see what we have left
up here that can save us.
준비 거의 다 됬어.
We're almost ready.
말이라도 좀 걸어줄까?
Do you want me to talk
아님 걍 조용히 있을까?
or just shut up?
멈춰요!
Stop!
나 너무 무서워.
I'm so scared.
날 봐.
Look at me.
알았지? 걍 날 계속 보고있어.
Ok? Just keep looking at me.
됐어요.
She's ready.
으아아!
Aah!
지상인들 본거지에서 말이지.
Yeah. That was me at the Grounder camp.
알잖아, 비명도 안지르려고 노력했던거, 근데 결국엔..
You now, I did everything I could
not scream, but eventually...
결국엔, 굴복했지
but eventually, you broke
다 불어버렸지.
and you told them everything.
넌 안그랬다고 말하고 싶은거겠지
왜냐면 넌 나보다 잘난놈이니까.
And you wouldn't have
because you're better than me.
그래 병신아.
Damn right.
난 너같은 배신자새끼가 아냐.
I'm not a traitor.
난 우리 위치에 대해
단 한마디도 나불대지 않았어.
I didn't tell them
where they could find us.
난 나불댔고.
And I did.
그래, 내가 나불댔지.
Yeah, I did.
그 놈들한테 3일내내 고문받은 뒤에 말야.
After they tortured me in
their prison camp for 3 days,
근데 봐봐라
but go ahead.
넌 나랑 똑같은 새끼 취급 받으면서도
You just keep believing,
여전히 네가 더 잘났다고 믿고 있지.
even if you are in here just like me.
알았어, 모여봐봐.
All right. Bring it in.
어쩔텐가?
Now what?
북쪽입니다.
It's coming from the north.
따라오도록.
On me.
켐벨은 살아있어. 끌어내리게.
Campbell's alive. Cut him down.
가자!
Let's go!
늦어서 죄송합니다.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
오염 세척처리를 해야만 했거든요.
We had to finish decontamination.
씽선생, 고맙네.
Thank you, Dr. Tsing.
화상입은 남자,
The man with the burns,
상태가 어떻죠?
how is he?
낫고 있어요.
He's improving.
전..그러니까 그와 얘길 좀 나눠보고 싶군요.
I... I'd like to talk to him.
각하, 의료시설엔 환자만 출입할 수 있습니다.
Sir, only patients are allowed in medical.
자리를 한 번 마련해보도록 하겠네.
We can arrange that.
이건 뭐죠?
What is this?
혈액투석 출입구에요.
It's a dialysis shunt.
방사능 노출에 대비해 모두에게 시술했죠.
We all have them in case of exposure.
(관통상의) 반대편을 보고 싶나요?
Would you like to see the exit wound?
랭스턴 상사가 현장에서 화살을 뽑아냈죠.
Sergeant Langston was forced to
push the arrow out in the field.
감사합니다 각하.
Thank you, sir.
여기 보관되어 있어요.
We've got it right here.
우리 운이 다한건 아닌가 보구나, 꼬마야.
We may be out of luck, little man.
이건 어디서 났니?
Where'd you get that?
언젠가 네게 두는 법을 가르쳐줄 수 있을지도 모르겠구나.
Maybe I'll teach you to play someday.
지상으로 향하는 함선
Ship-to-ground.
미친 짓이긴 해..
I can't be that crazy.
저 하얀문 보이니?
You see that white door?
에어락이라고 한단다.
It's called an airlock.
우리가 탈 것이 바로 저기 있단다.
Our ride is on the other side.
미사일이지.
It's a missile.
아이러닉하지?
Ironic, huh?
우리 선조들은 저걸로 세상을 멸망시켰는데
Our ancestors used them
to destroy the world.
우린 귀환하기 위해 사용하다니.
We're gonna use one to get back to it.
좋은 소식은 여기까지였고
That's the good news.
안좋은 소식은...
The bad news is...
이 밖으로 나가지 않는 이상
저기로 갈 방법이 없단 거란다.
we can't get to it unless we go outside.
좀 어떤가?
How is she?
글쎄, 일단 수술 중에 죽진 않았죠..
Well, she survived the surgery.
어떻게 했냐고 물어보진 마시구요.
Don't ask me how.
정말 용기있는 아이에요.
She's a courageous kid.
이 아이들이 가진 걸 한가지만 대보라면,
That's one thing these kids have
그게 바로 용기일게야.
is courage.
벨라미는 나가고 싶어 안달이 났더군.
Bellamy can't wait to get back out there.
아마, 그는 친구들을 돕고 싶어하는 것뿐이겠죠.
Well, he wants to help his friends.
에비, 모두가 그럼 심정일거네만
We all want to find out
what happened to them, Abby,
적의 정체를 명확히 하고
but not without a plan
작전을 세우기 전엔 요원한 일이야.
or a clear idea of what we're up against.
수색팀을 보내지 않았죠? 아닌가요?
You didn't send that
search team out, did you?
그들은 못박혀 죽어있었지.
Those men were crucified.
경고겠지. 난 이걸 아주 심각하게 받아들이고 있다네.
That's a warning I intend
to take very seriously.
아이들을 찾기위해 모든 노력을 아끼지 않을거야.
We'll search high and
low for the missing kids,
내 약속하지,
you have my word,
하지만 이 곳의 안전이 우선이야.
but not before we've secured this camp.
그놈들이 존 머피를 고문했다구요.
They tortured John Murphy.
제스퍼 조단의 가슴엔 창을 박아넣었죠.
They put a spear into
Jasper Jordan's chest.
더이상 지체해선 안된다구요.
We can't wait.
마르커스...
Marcus...
제발..
Please.
미안하네.
I'm sorry.
이미 결정난 사안이네.
I've made my decision.
좀 나아졌나보군.
You're feeling better.
넌 누구지?
Who are you?
링컨은 어딨고?
Where's Lincoln?
난 나이코다.
I'm Nyko.
링컨의 친구지.
그래서 널 도운거야.
Lincoln is my friend.
That's why I helped you.
일어날 수 있군, 좋아.
You stand. Good.
왜냐면 이제부터 도망가야 할테니까.
Because now you should run.
링컨 어딨냐니까?
Where's Lincoln?
그가 한 일에 대한, 대가를 치르고 있지.
He's answering for what he's done.
너흴 돕는 바람에, 우리 부족은 리퍼들이 나타나도
Because he helped you,
our clan is vulnerable.
대적할 수 없을만큼 취약해졌다.
If the reapers come, we
can't even fight them off.
잠깐 기다려.
Wait, wait.
그 놈들이 링컨을 붙잡았단 말이야?
Are you saying that they caught him?
안돼 기다려, 그 놈들이 링컨를 죽일꺼라고.
No, no. Wait. They'll kill him.
우리가 뭐라도 해야되.
We have to do something.
제발.. 친구랬잖아.
Please. You said he's your friend.
우리가 뭐라도 해야한다고!
We have to do something.
이미 했잖아..
I did do something.
널 구했지.
I saved your life.
이제 뛰기나 해.
Now run.
윽!
Unh!
날 구해준 건 고마워하고 있어.
Thank you for saving my life.
윽!
Augh!
Ai laik okteivia kom skai kru,
(난 하늘인 옥타비아다!)
너희에게 볼 일이 있어왔다.
and you have something I want.
Ai laik indra kom trigeda.
Chit yu gaf?
원하는게 뭐냐? 하늘인 옥타비아. 라고 했다.
I said what do you want,
Octavia of the sky people?
링컨
Lincoln.
안되
No.
으아아!
Agh!
그만. 나이코는 유일한 치료사다.
Enough. Nyko is our only healer.
좋아, 그럼 내가 말대로 하겠군.
Good. Then you'll do as I say.
으아아!
Agh!
링컨을 내가 마지막으로 봤던 장소로 데려와라.
Bring Lincoln to the place I saw him last.
그가 위치를 알고 있다.
He knows where that is.
그와 당신만 와라.
Just you and him, no one else.
딴 놈이 얼씬거리기라도 한다면,
If I see anyone else,
치료사를 죽이겠다.
I'll kill your healer.
밤까지 기다리지.
You have until dark.
일어서!
Get up.
느껴지니?
You felt that?
예, 느껴져요.
Yes, I felt that.
좋아. 그럼 왼쪽.
Good. Now the left.
암것도?
Anything?
다시 해봐요.
Try it again.
다시 해보라니까요!
Try it again!
핀
Finn.
레이븐, 뭐라도 느껴지면
Raven, I want you to tell me
나에게 말해주렴, 알았지?
when you feel something, ok?
거기요.
There.
레이븐, 아무래도 왼쪽 다리 신경에
Raven, it appears that you have
심한 손상이 있는거 같아.
significant damage to the
nerves in your left leg.
나아질까요?
Will it get better?
일단은 목발을 짚고 다녀야 하겠지만
For now, you'll need crutches,
일단은 살았잖니,
but you're alive,
더이상 아프지도 않고.
and you're not in pain anymore.
하지만 여전히 불구잖아요.
But I'm still crippled.
둘만의 시간을 좀 줘야겠구나.
I'm gonna give you two some time.
계속 네 얘기만 했어.
We always talk about you.
뭔 말했는지 궁금하지 않아?
Don't you want to hear about my day?
나 너무 피곤해.
I'm so tired.
좀 쉬어..
Get some rest.
저기..
Hey.
나 깨어나면,
When I wake up,
여기 있지마.
don't be here.
뭔 소릴 하는거야?
What are you talking about?
항상 내 곁에 있었지,
You were here for me like always,
친구들이 저 밖에 있어,
and our friends are out there,
넌 그들을 데려와야 해.
and you need to go get them.
월러스 대통령이 뭐래?
What did president Wallace say?
쇼우의 시신을 보여줬어.
He showed me Shaw's body.
화살로 난 상처마냥 보이더군
It looked like an arrow wound.
글쎄, 어쩌면 그게 화살로 난 상처이니까 그런걸지도 모르지.
Well, maybe because it is an arrow wound.
아니면 그렇게 생각하게 하려는 거겠지.
Or that's what they want us to think.
야! 저들이 날조했을지도 모른다고.
What? They could have doctored it.
클라크, 너 살짝 돌은 사람같다고..
Clarke, you sound like a crazy person.
왜 그렇게 트집잡지 못해 안달이야?
Why do you want to screw this up for us?
당췌 뭔일인지 모르겠단 말야.
I don't know what this is.
안전하다고..
This is... safe.
음식, 진짜 침대, 옷가지들,
This is food, a real bed, clothes,
그리고 내 개인적인 취미도 즐길수 있고..
and my personal favorite...
지상인들에게 창맞을 일도 없다는 그런 의미라고..
not getting speared by Grounders.
계속 이러고도, 우리가 여기
How long do you think
they'll let us stay here
머무를 수 있을꺼라 생각하는거야?
if you keep this up?
누가 협박이라도 한거니?
Did someone threaten you?
허. 아니아니.
Heh. No. No.
상식이지.
It's common sense.
보라고. 우린 여기서 손님대접을 받고 있다고 죄수취급 당하는게 아니라.
Look. We're guests here, not prisoners.
사람을 거짓말쟁이로 매도하고, 은혜도 모르는 상놈처럼 행동하는데
What would you do with a guest
who kept calling you a liar
계속 손님 대접 해줄 사람이 있을 꺼라 생각해?
and generally acted like an ungrateful ass?
그 은혜도 모르는 상놈을 쫓아내야지.
Kick the ungrateful ass out.
지금 우릴 위험에 빠뜨리고 있는게 바로 너라고.
Right now, biggest threat to us is you.
미사일 베이 에어락 개방.
Missile bay airlock open.
장관코드 승인됨.
Chancellor code accepted.
미사일 자동발사절차 진행중.
Automated missile launch
sequence commencing.
미사일 발사 15분전.
Missile launch in T-minus 15 minutes.
좋아.
Yes.
잠금 해제.
Override lockout.
Don't want to miss our ride, little man.
차 놓치긴 싫지, 꼬마야.
그래.
Yes.
걱정말렴. 산소는 슈트 전체에 공급되니까.
Don't worry. This o2 feeds the whole suit.
뭔 기분인진 안다만..
(새걸 가져올 시간이 없어)
I know how you feel.
미사일 발사 7분전.
Missile launch in T-minus
7 minutes and counting.
7분이라..
7 minutes
가로질러서 착지하고
to fly across the ring, stick the landing,
발사되기 전까지 기어올라간다.
and climb into a missile
before it launches.
그쯤이야.
No problem.
꽉잡으렴, 꼬마야.
Hold on, little man.
윽!
Unh!
꼬마야, 이런 짓 다신 하지 말자꾸나.
Little man, let's never do that again.
안돼.
No.
미사일 발사 4분전.
Missile launch in T-minus
4 minutes and counting.
아냐.
No.
아냐. 허? 아니라고!
No. Huh? No!
아빠
Dad.
내 아들
My son.
아들아
Son.
산소결핍증이야
It's oxygen deprivation.
일어나세요
Stand up.
싫어.
No.
아직 끝나지 않았아요.
You're not done yet.
난 끝났어.
I am done.
나는!
I am!
사람들에겐 아직 당신이 필요해요.
Our people still need you.
아냐, 아냐.
No. No.
그들을 지상으로 보냈다고,
I got them to the ground.
내 소임을 다했어.
I did my job.
제겐 뭐라고 하셨죠?
What would you tell me to do?
이건 불공평해.
That's not fair.
살으라고 하셨죠.
You would tell me to live.
당신께선 이미 너무 많은 희생을 치뤘어요.
You've sacrificed so much.
당신의 삶은 단지 어려운 결정이나
Your life can be more
비참한 결말보단
than just impossible decisions
훨씬 가치 있다구요.
and a tragic end.
삶을 택할 수 있어요.
You can choose to live.
보고싶었단다. 아들아.
I miss you, son.
매일 매일.
Every day.
아빠, 전 항상 함께하고 있어요.
I'm always with you, dad.
할 수 있어요.
You can do this.
미사일 발사 2분전.
Missile launch in T-minus
two minutes and counting.
탄두 무장해체.
Disarm the warhead.
미사일 낙하산 확인
Check the missile's parachute.
밀봉 확인.
Confirm the hard seal.
산소통 잊지 마시구요.
Don't forget your air tank.
집에 갈 시간이야..
Time to go home.
일어나.
Get up.
친구들 찾으러 가야지.
We're going after them.
그럴 때가 되긴 했지
It's about time.
잠깐, 기다려. 난 어쩌고?
Wait, wait. What about me?
잠깐. 안돼! 뭐하는거야?
Wait. No! What are you doing?
함께 간다.
He's coming with us.
말도 안돼.
No way.
이 놈은 지상인 감옥에 잡혀가봤지.
He's been to the Grounder prison camp.
맞아, 그래. 내가 너흴 안내할께.
He's right. Ok. I can bring you there.
저기, 문열리는 소리야.
Hey. Sterling just signaled.
누군가 오고 있어.
Someone's coming.
피아노는 처음 쳐보는데
First time I ever played it.
한번 쳐봐, 반하게 될껄.
Cool. I loved it.
랭스턴
Langston.
얌마, 어딜가?
Where you going, man?
영화날 인데.
Tonight's movie night.
좀 봐줘, 의사양반이 한번 더 치료받아야 된댔단 말야
I got to pass. Doc says
I got one more treatment.
의료시설엔 환자만 출입할 수 있습니다.
Only patients are allowed in medical.
3, 2, 1, 발사.
3, 2, 1, launch.
돌아가는 꼬라질 보아하니 날 죽여야 겠구만
Looks like you'll have to kill me.
링컨
Lincoln.
다쳤잖아!
He's hurt!
죽여야 했는데..
He should be dead.
미안
Sorry.
리퍼다!
Reapers!
흐야아아!
Hyah!
링컨
Lincoln.
옥타비아! 옥타비아!
Octavia! Octavia!
링컨
Lincoln.
옥타비아!
Octavia!
하 하!
Ha ha!
어쩌면 자네들을 다시 만날 수 있을지도 모르겠군
May we meet again.
아무도 우릴 못봤겠지?
You don't think anyone saw us?
쉬.. 잘 숨어나 있어
Shh. Keep it down.
늦었잖아
You're late.
벨라미가 얠 데려오자 그래서 말야
Bellamy decided to bring company.
이 놈이 놈들 캠프에 가본 유일한 녀석이라구요.
He's the only person
that's been in their camp.
이거 받고, 내 아들 꼭 좀 찾아줘
Here. Find my son.
그 아이 이름은 네이쓴 밀러야.
His name is Nathan Miller.
아이들 꼭 데려와 줘
Bring them home.
랭스톤
Langston.
뭔 짓을 해놓은 거야?
What are they doing to you?
앤야?
(시즌1에서 클라크랑 협상을
하기도 했던 부족여왕임)
Anya?
- 이렇게 자막쟁이 되는건가.... - Made By. karmiss
- synced and corrected by chamallow -
- www.addic7ed.com -